[{
	"id": 0,
    "question": "Which of the following is true for variable names in Python?",
    "a": "unlimited length",
    "b": "all private members must have leading and trailing underscores",
    "c": "underscore and ampersand are the only two special characters allowed",
    "d": "none of the mentioned",
    "answer": "unlimited length"
},
{
	"id": 1,
    "question": "The output of the line of code shown below is:\nnot(10<20) and not(10>30)",
    "a": "True",
    "b": "False",
    "c": "Error",
    "d": "No output",
    "answer": "False"
},
{
	"id": 2,
    "question": "What is the output of the following?\nfor i in range(int(2.0)):\n    print(i)",
    "a": "0.0 1.0",
    "b": "0 1",
    "c": "error",
    "d": "none of the mentioned",
    "answer": "0 1"
},
{
	"id": 3,
    "question": "What arithmetic operators cannot be used with strings ?",
    "a": "+",
    "b": "*",
    "c": "–",
    "d": "All of the mentioned",
    "answer": "–"
},
{
	"id": 4,
    "question": "Suppose list1 is [2, 33, 222, 14, 25], What is list1[-1] ?",
    "a": "Error",
    "b": "None",
    "c": "25",
    "d": "2",
    "answer": "25"
},
{
	"id": 5,
    "question": "Which of these about a dictionary is false?",
    "a": "The values of a dictionary can be accessed using keys",
    "b": "The keys of a dictionary can be accessed using values",
    "c": "Dictionaries aren’t ordered",
    "d": "Dictionaries are mutable",
    "answer": "The keys of a dictionary can be accessed using values"
},
{
	"id": 6,
    "question": "What is returned by math.modf(1.0)?",
    "a": "(0.0, 1.0)",
    "b": "(1.0, 0.0)",
    "c": "(0.5, 1)",
    "d": "(0.5, 1.0)",
    "answer": "(0.0, 1.0)"
},
{
	"id": 7,
    "question": "What is the use of seek() method in files?",
    "a": "sets the file’s current position at the offset",
    "b": "sets the file’s previous position at the offset",
    "c": "sets the file’s current position within the file",
    "d": "none of the mentioned",
    "answer": "sets the file’s current position at the offset"
},
{
	"id": 8,
    "question": "Suppose B is a subclass of A, to invoke the __init__ method in A from B, what is the line of code you should write?",
    "a": "A.__init__(self)",
    "b": "B.__init__(self)",
    "c": "A.__init__(B)",
    "d": "B.__init__(self)",
    "answer": "A.__init__(self)"
},
{
	"id": 9,
    "question": "Which of these is false about recursion?",
    "a": "Recursive function can be replaced by a non-recursive function",
    "b": "Recursive functions usually take more memory space than non-recursive function",
    "c": "Recursive functions run faster than non-recursive function",
    "d": "Recursion makes programs easier to understand",
    "answer": "Recursive functions run faster than non-recursive function"
},
{
	"id": 10,
    "question": "What is the output of this expression, 3*1**3?",
    "a": "27",
    "b": "9",
    "c": "3",
    "d": "1",
    "answer": "3"
},
{
	"id": 11,
    "question": "Which of the following expressions involves coercion when evaluated in Python?",
    "a": "4.7 – 1.5",
    "b": "7.9 * 6.3",
    "c": "1.7 % 2",
    "d": "3.4 + 4.6",
    "answer": "1.7 % 2"
},
{
	"id": 12,
    "question": "Given a string example=”hello” what is the output of example.count(l)",
    "a": "2",
    "b": "1",
    "c": "None",
    "d": "0",
    "answer": "2"
},
{
	"id": 13,
    "question": "To which of the following the “in” operator can be used to check if an item is in it?",
    "a": "Lists",
    "b": "Dictionary",
    "c": "Set",
    "d": "All of the mentioned",
    "answer": "All of the mentioned"
},
{
	"id": 14,
    "question": "Python supports the creation of anonymous functions at runtime, using a construct called __________",
    "a": "Lambda",
    "b": "pi",
    "c": "anonymous",
    "d": "None of the mentioned",
    "answer": "Lambda"
},
{
	"id": 15,
    "question": "How many keyword arguments can be passed to a function in a single function call?",
    "a": "zero",
    "b": "one",
    "c": "zero or more",
    "d": "one or more",
    "answer": "zero or more"
},
{
	"id": 16,
    "question": "Which of the following functions returns a value in degrees, counterclockwise from the horizontal right?",
    "a": "heading()",
    "b": "degrees()",
    "c": "position()",
    "d": "window_height()",
    "answer": "heading()"
},
{
	"id": 17,
    "question": "What is Instantiation in terms of OOP terminology?",
    "a": "Deleting an instance of class",
    "b": "Modifying an instance of class",
    "c": "Copying an instance of class",
    "d": "Creating an instance of class",
    "answer": "Creating an instance of class"
},
{
	"id": 18,
    "question": "Which of the following statements is true?",
    "a": "The standard exceptions are needed to be imported manually",
    "b": "The standard exceptions are automatically imported into Python programs",
    "c": "When there is a deviation from the rules of a programming language, a semantic error is thrown",
    "d": "If any exception is thrown in try block, else block is executed",
    "answer": "The standard exceptions are automatically imported into Python programs"
},
{
	"id": 19,
    "question": "What is the output of the following code? {a**2 for a in range(4)}",
    "a": "{1, 4, 9, 16}",
    "b": "{0, 1, 4, 9, 16}",
    "c": "Error",
    "d": "{0, 1, 4, 9}",
    "answer": "{0, 1, 4, 9}"
},
{
	"id": 20,
    "question": "What is the value of the following expression:\n24//6%3, 24//4//2",
    "a": "(1,3)",
    "b": "(0,3)",
    "c": "(1,0)",
    "d": "(3,1)",
    "answer": "(1,3)"
},
{
	"id": 21,
    "question": "What is the output of print 0.1 + 0.2 == 0.3?",
    "a": "True",
    "b": "False",
    "c": "Machine dependent",
    "d": "Error",
    "answer": "False"
},
{
	"id": 22,
    "question": "Fill in the blanks: The formatting method {1:<10} represents the ___________ positional argument, _________ justified in a 10 character wide field.",
    "a": "first, right",
    "b": "second, left",
    "c": "first, left",
    "d": "second, right",
    "answer": "second, left"
},
{
	"id": 23,
    "question": "Which of the following is the use of id() function in python?",
    "a": "Id returns the identity of the object",
    "b": "Every object doesn’t have a unique id",
    "c": "Every object doesn’t have a unique id",
    "d": "None of the mentioned",
    "answer": "Id returns the identity of the object"
},
{
	"id": 24,
    "question": "What is the base case in the Merge Sort algorithm when it is solved recursively?",
    "a": "n=0",
    "b": "n=1",
    "c": "A list of length one",
    "d": "An empty list",
    "answer": "A list of length one"
},
{
	"id": 25,
    "question": "Which of the following functions helps us to randomize the items of a list?",
    "a": "seed",
    "b": "randomise",
    "c": "shuffle",
    "d": "uniform",
    "answer": "shuffle"
},
{
	"id": 26,
    "question": "What does built-in function help do in context of classes?",
    "a": "Determines the object name of any value",
    "b": "Determines the class identifiers of any value",
    "c": "Determines class description of any built-in type",
    "d": "Determines class description of any user-defined built-in type",
    "answer": "Determines class description of any built-in type"
},
{
	"id": 27,
    "question": "Methods of a class that provide access to private members of the class are called as ______ and ______",
    "a": "getters/setters",
    "b": "__repr__/__str__",
    "c": "user-defined functions/in-built functions",
    "d": "user-defined functions/in-built functions",
    "answer": "getters/setters"
},
{
	"id": 28,
    "question": "What is the output of the below program ?\nx = 50\ndef func(x):\n    print('x is', x)\n    x = 2\n    print('Changed local x to', x)\nfunc(x)\nprint('x is now', x)",
    "a": "x is now 50",
    "b": "x is now 2",
    "c": "x is now 100",
    "d": "None of the mentioned",
    "answer": "x is now 50"
},
{
	"id": 29,
    "question": " Is Python code compiled or interpreted?",
    "a": "Python code is only compiled",
    "b": "Python code is both compiled and interpreted",
    "c": "Python code is only interpreted",
    "d": "Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted",
    "answer": "Python code is both compiled and interpreted"
}]